Ben Sharp

Web Development

Flat 22, The Mill Apartments 1-7 Mill Lane London, NW61AQ Tel: 07590075001

Email: bfwsharp@gmail.com
Portfolio: ben-sharp.com

SUMMARY

Hello! I'm Ben, a creative, freelance web developer with 11 years experience specialising in front-end technologies namely JavaScript to ES6, HTML and CSS. I am passionate about building effective, user friendly web experiences.

Whilst being a front-end developer, I am always keen to learn and expand my skill set to all areas of the development process. I am currently looking for new opportunities to work, share, collaborate and learn with good people.

EXPERIENCE

Zzish - Senior Front-end Developer

December 2018 – Present

- Responsible for management of front-end team's development timings and job assignment
- Implemented new tech such like Styled Components and Apollo into the front-end stack
- Onboarding and mentoring of junior members of the team

Tech stack: React | Apollo GraphQL | Relay Classic & Modern | Styled Components & PostCSS | JavaScript/Typescript/FlowJS | Webpack 3/4 | Node/Express

Zzish - Front-end Developer

January 2018 - December 2018

- Development of front-end architecture using React / Relay in Node-powered workflow
- Focus on performance, usability and up-to-date practices
- Focus on own learning and expanding my own skill set in a modern web stack
- Collaborated closely with designers to create beautiful, fast and functional interfaces

 Occasionally worked in a full stack role when required to help with workload and to pique my own interest in the overall development process

Tech stack: React | Relay Classic & Modern | PostCSS | SASS | JavaScript/FlowJS | Webpack 3 | Jenkins | CircleCl | Bootstrap | Pug

International Railway Journal, Cornwall UK - Freelance

January 2017 - January 2018

- Providing consultation, project management and support for the company's subscription based industry data visualisation application.
- Diagnosing and rectifying issues
- Maintaining and developing new application features
- Implementing SSL security
- Providing managed hosting service

Tech stack: HTML | CSS/SASS | JS | jQuery | AngularJS | PHP | ExpressionEngine | Vagrant | Bootstrap

Your Favourite Story, London UK - Freelance

May - June 2017

- Joined the agency interactive team to develop a point of sale touch table application for Mercedes-Benz UK showrooms in vanilla JS using bespoke in house framework.
- Worked closely with the project management and design team to deliver in a tight timeframe.
- Maintenance on various other Mercedes-Benz platforms.

Tech stack: HTML | CSS/SASS | JS | jQuery | JSON | GreensockJS | SVG | HandlebarsJS | Bootstrap | Bitbucket | JIRA | Sketch

Antidote, London UK - Freelance

November 2014 - 2018

- Lead the development of multiple agency web projects.
- Provided digital consultation and support to the agency.

Tech stack: AS2/3 | Photoshop | Illustrator | HTML | CSS/SASS/LESS | JS | jQuery | Gulp | Webpack | GreensockJS | SVG | Bootstrap | GitHub | PHP | Wordpress | Ink for Emails

ThirtyThree, London UK - Freelance

January - November 2014

- Built multiple websites using custom in-house CMS.
- Developed numerous sliders, quizzes and video player modules.
- Performed on going maintenance and updates to agency client websites

Tech stack: HTML | CSS/SASS | JS | jQuery | JSON | XML | PHP | Concrete5 | Bootstrap | Mercurial

Everywhere, London UK - Freelance

April - December 2013

- Developed a scrolling parallax visual product showcase for Virgin Atlantic's new Dreamliner 787.
- Major site functionality updates to an ecommerce Wordpress build.
- HTML Email campaigns.

Tech stack: HTML | CSS | JS | jQuery | JSON | PHP | Wordpress + ACF | Bootstrap | Trello

The Minimart, London UK - Creative Web Developer

November 2008 - March 2013

- Built client websites, games, banner campaigns
- Worked closely with managing director in pitching for new business
- Maintained performance of existing client websites
- Maintained agency I.T infrastructure
- Lead the development of agency website

Tech stack: Flash | AS2/3 | Greensock | HTML | CSS | JS | jQuery | XML | JSON | PHP | Photoshop | Illustrator | TortoiseSVN | Doubleclick | cPanel | Plesk

EDUCATION

Qantm (University of Middlesex), London - Diploma

2006 - 2008

Web design and development.

Impington College International Sixth Form - A Level

2000 - 2002

Drama, English, Media Studies (B, C, D)

Impington Village College - GCSE

1995 - 2000

10 GCSE grades A-C

REFERENCES

Available from long term direct clients and agencies upon request.